# Rithik Banerjee

## .Net Developer

Passionate software developer with around one year of experience in .Net framework, that includes understanding system requirements, designing architecture, development, testing, updating and support of commercial application. Extensive knowledge in object oriented programming, client side web development, database management and version

- banerjee13rithik@gmail.com
- rithikbanerjee.github.io/profile
- twitter.com/banerjee\_rithik
- github.com/RithikBanerjee

- (+91) 990 347 1021
- linkedin.com/in/RithikBanerjee
- live:banerjee13rithik
  - stackoverflow.com/users/13430233

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Web Developer

# Opticodes Technologies 🗷

07/2019 - Present Kanpur, Uttar Pradesh Full Time Web Developer responsible for planing architecture, coding, versioning and maintaining a GST portal and a GSP

- Developed custom, general use modules and components namely, Query Creator, Dapper Method Store, Request Handler, Validation Engine, etc.
- Built a general purpose class library to import data in bulk from excel sheet to database irrespective of its template and header.
- Created E-invoice and E-way bill generating portal using NIC APIS.
- Researched and evaluted technologies that created value for the company.

# iOS Developer

## TenPi Technologies 🗷

05/2017 - 07/2017

Kolkata, West Bengal

Intern iOS Developer responsible for building a iOS app using Xcode 7.3.1 which would finds nearby bluetooth devices.

- Built a beacon iOS application on Xcode using Bluetooth 4.0.
- Responsible for the version maintenance of the iOS application.
- Designed the UI/UX for the iOS application using Adobe Illustrator.
- Integrated cloud based database for registered beacon devices in the iOS application.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS



#### **PROJECTS**

Music playing web application based on Django framework.

Excel Data Importer (01/2020 - 03/2020)

ORM module to import excel data based on .Net framework.

GSP SDK (11/2019 - 02/2020) 2

Goods & Services Tax module based on Rest APIs.

Iris Detector (09/2018 - 04/2019) 🗗

Python module used in iris based bio-metric authentication.

#### **HOBBIES**

Article Writing 🗗

Author at C#Corner.

Competitive Coding 🗹

Certified in Problem Solving, Rest API, Python, Java & JS.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **B. Tech in Computer Science**

Jalpaiguri Government Engineering College 🗷

2015 - 2019 West Bengal

## **LANGUAGES**

Enalish

Hindi Full Professional Proficiency

Full Professional Proficiency